Pavel Palancica

pavel.palancica@gmail.com | +40 758-972-924 | Bucharest, Romania https://www.linkedin.com/in/pavelpalancica/ https://github.com/ppalancica/

iOS Developer

Result-oriented iOS developer with over 7 years of experience writing highly readable, clean, and maintainable code. Developed and contributed to more than 10 iOS apps for both startups and medium size clients. Ability to collaborate with both colleagues and non-technical clients and quickly come up with solutions.

Experience

ADORE ME, Bucharest, Romania • January 2020 - Present

- Architected, developed, and released new features on the iOS app
- Updated legacy code from Objective-C to Swift and adapted the app to the new REST API endpoints
- Improved architecture moving from MVC to MVVM and Coordinator

Pentalog, Cluj-Napoca, Romania • March 2019 – December 2019

- Worked on a popular iOS app that offers trip advice to people. Developed new features on the Trips section: Article and Photo reusable components, ability to save Trip Items to specific trips
- Created new onboarding screens for A / B Testing
- Updated UI code based on latest design requirements and also to reflect new data coming from backend APIs

ALOOMPA, Nashville, Tennessee, United States • December 2016 - December 2017

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vidcon-2017/id890603641?mt=8

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/2017-reebok-crossfit-games/id1240868782?mt=8

- Fixed over 600 out of 700 Xcode warnings and refactored huge parts of the code (updated deprecated classes / methods, added missing code). Compilation time went down from 3 mins to 30-50 seconds
- Architected and implemented new features of the Fest App iOS project (support for multiple types of push notifications, deep linking, artist
 tours). That increased customer engagement rate by more than 10%. Some new features required updates to the Model layer, and
 correctly mapping the updated JSON with the Core Data model entities
- Implemented custom, dynamic, modular user interfaces (table views with multiple types of resizable cells, stack views with resizable sub-views, including embedded collection views). As a result, custom UI configurations were done up to 4 times faster, compared to how it was previously implemented using scroll views
- Wrote a Form Engine component, which reduced development time from 6-8 hours to 1-3 hours for the Enter to Win feature
- · Fixed the maps overlays issues, which reduced some of the technical debt, but also led to more satisfied users and clients
- Successfully submitted over 10 client apps to the App Store, never missing a final release deadline
- Wrote code to access RESTful services, converted JSON objects to Core Data entities and vice-versa

ICITIZEN, Nashville, Tennessee, United States • January 2015 – October 2016

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/icitizen/id725655449?mt=8

- Architected, developed, and released the icitizen iOS app (v.2) in under 3 months (team of 3)
- Implemented custom user interfaces using Interface Builder and programmatically
- Wrote code to access RESTful services, converted JSON objects to Core Data entities and vice-versa
- Configured Jenkins to pull app's source code from Github and create new builds. That saved about 3-5h / week

TRAMBON GRUP, Lipoveni, Moldova • November 2012 – December 2013

- Created 2 iOS apps in the Utilities and Productivity categories
- Updated existing apps, tested and submitted them to the App Store
- Designed MySQL databases and contributed to web front-end development

CEDACRI INTERNATIONAL, Chisinau, Moldova • February 2011 – May 2011

- Wrote C# code to interact with internal databases. Wrote unit tests
- Created an internal vacation scheduling application which saved administrative staff time

Skills

iOS Development

- Proficient in Objective-C and Swift. Familiar with C/C++ and Java.
- UIKit, GCD, Core Animation, Auto Layout, iOS memory management, Core Data, Storyboards
- Design Patterns (MVC, Target-Action, Delegation, Observer, Singleton)
- Git. Push Notifications. Jenkins continuous integration. Automated Testing

General Software Development

- Familiar with fundamentals of web, such as HTML, CSS, JSON, XML, JavaScript, and Ajax
- Object oriented design, data structures, networking, concurrency, databases

Education

Maharishi University of Management (Fairfield, Iowa, United States)

Master of Science in Computer Science (2014 - 2017)

Academy of Economic Studies of Moldova (Chisinau, Moldova)

Master of Business Administration (2011 – 2013)

Moldova State University (Chisinau, Moldova)

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (2008 – 2011)